zkoss.org 2019-05-13

# Privacy | ZK

_Last updated: May 18, 2018_

Thanks for entrusting Potix Corporation, who creates and maintains ZK, with your projects, and your personal information. Holding onto your private information is a serious responsibility, and we want you to know how we're handling it.

## The short version

We collect your information only with your consent; we only collect the minimum amount of personal information that is necessary to fulfill the purpose of your interaction with us; we don't sell it to third parties; and we only use it as this Privacy Policy describes. Of course, the short version doesn't tell you everything, so please read on for more details!

## What information ZK collects and why

### Information from website browsers and products

If you're just browsing the website, we collect the same basic information that most websites collect. We use common internet technologies, such as cookies and web server logs. This is stuff we collect from everybody, whether they have an account or not.

The information we collect about all visitors to our website includes the visitor’s browser type, language preference, referring site, additional websites requested, and the date and time of each visitor request. We also collect potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses.

### Why do we collect this?

We collect this information to better understand how our website visitors use ZK, and to monitor and protect the security of the website.

### Information from users with accounts

If you create an account with email, we will require some basic information at the time of account creation. You will create your own user name and password, and we will ask you for a valid email account, your name, country, industry and company name.

You can give us more information if you want to, and this may include “User Personal Information."

"User Personal Information" is any information about one of our users which could, alone or together with other information, personally identify him or her. Information such as a user name and password, an email address, a real name, and a photograph are examples of “User Personal Information.”

User Personal Information does not include aggregated, non-personally identifying information. We may use aggregated, non-personally identifying information to operate, improve, and optimize our website, product and service.

Why do we collect this?

  * We need your User Personal Information to create your account, and to provide the services you request such as giving you access to the files according to your account permission.
  * We use your User Personal Information, specifically your user name, to identify you on ZK.
  * We use it to fill out your profile and share that profile with other users if you ask us to.
  * We will use your email address to communicate with you, if you’ve subscribed to receive related notifications about ZK, and when necessary.
  * We limit our use of your User Personal Information to the purposes listed in this Privacy Policy.

## What information ZK does not collect

We do not intentionally collect sensitive personal information, such as social security numbers, genetic data, health information, or religious information. However if you elect to publicly post personally identifying or sensitive information in ZK website such as in forum question or answer posts, it is not subject to the Privacy Policy listed here, and you are responsible for it. Additionally, voluntarily publicizing such information means that you lose any privacy rights you might normally have with regards to that information.

If you're a child under the age of 13, you may not have an account on ZK. ZK does not knowingly collect information from or direct any of our content specifically to children under 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that you are a user who is under the age of 13, we will unfortunately have to close your account.

## How we share the information we collect

We do not share, sell, rent, or trade User Personal Information with third parties for their commercial purposes.

We do share certain aggregated, non-personally identifying information with others about how our users, collectively, use ZK. However, we do not sell this information to advertisers or marketers.

We may occasionally embed content from third party sites, such as YouTube, and that content may include ads. While we try to minimize the amount of ads our embedded content contains, we can't always control what third parties show.

We may share User Personal Information with your permission, so we can perform services you have requested.

We may share User Personal Information with a limited number of third-party vendors who process it on our behalf to provide or improve our service, and who have agreed to privacy restrictions similar to our own Privacy Policy. Our vendors perform services such as payment processing, customer support ticketing, network data transmission, and other similar services. Here in ZK we care who to work with and partner with only the service providers who we believe maintain an acceptable standard of data security compliance such as Salesforce, Freshdesk, AWS and Google.

We may share User Personal Information if we are involved in a merger, sale, or acquisition. If any such change of ownership happens, we will ensure that it is under terms that preserve the confidentiality of User Personal Information, and we will notify you on our website or by email before any transfer of your User Personal Information. The organization receiving any User Personal Information will have to honor any promises we have made in our Privacy Policy or in our Terms of Service.

## Our use of cookies and tracking

### Cookies

ZK uses cookies to make interactions with our service easy and meaningful. We use cookies (and similar technologies, like HTML5 localStorage) to keep you logged in, remember your preferences, giving you access to requested resources and provide information for future development of ZK.

A cookie is a small piece of text that our web server stores on your computer or mobile device, which your browser sends to us when you return to our site. Cookies do not necessarily identify you if you are merely visiting ZK; however, a cookie may store a unique identifier for each logged in user. The cookies ZK sets are essential for the operation of the website, or are used for performance or functionality. By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your computer or device. If you disable your browser or device’s ability to accept cookies, you will not be able to log in or use ZK’s services.

### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics as a third party tracking service, but we don’t use it to track you individually or collect your User Personal Information. We use Google Analytics to collect information about how our website performs and how our users, in general, navigate through and use ZK. This helps us evaluate our users' use of ZK; compile statistical reports on activity; and improve our content and website performance.

Google Analytics gathers certain simple, non-personally identifying information over time, such as your browser type, internet service provider, referring and exit pages, time stamp, and similar data about your use of ZK. We do not link this information to any of your personal information such as your user name. ZK will not, nor will we allow any third party to, use the Google Analytics tool to track our users individually; collect any User Personal Information other than IP address; or correlate your IP address with your identity. Google provides further information about its own privacy practices and offers a [browser add-on to opt out of Google Analytics tracking](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

Certain pages on our site may set other third-party cookies. For example, we may embed content, such as videos, from another site that sets a cookie. While we try to minimize these third party cookies, we can’t always control what cookies this third party content sets.

## How ZK secures your information

ZK takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect User Personal Information from unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction; maintain data accuracy; and help ensure the appropriate use of User Personal Information. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## ZK's global privacy practices

Information that we collect will be stored and processed in the United States and Taiwan in accordance with this Privacy Policy. However, we understand that we have users from different countries and regions with different privacy expectations, and we try to meet those needs. We provide the same standard of privacy protection to all our users around the world, regardless of their country of origin or location, and we are proud of the levels of notice, choice, accountability, security, data integrity, access, and recourse we provide. We work hard to comply with the applicable data privacy laws wherever we do business.

In particular:

  * ZK provides clear methods of unambiguous, informed consent at the time of data collection, when we do collect your personal data.
  * We collect only the minimum amount of personal data necessary, unless you choose to provide more. We encourage you to only give us the amount of data you are comfortable sharing.
  * We offer you simple methods of accessing, correcting, or deleting the data we have collected.
  * We provide our users notice, choice, accountability, security, and access, and we limit the purpose for processing.

## Resolving Complaints

If you have concerns about the way ZK is handling your User Personal Information, please let us know immediately. We want to help. You may email us directly at [info@zkoss.org](mailto:info@zkoss.org) with the subject line "Privacy Shield Concerns." 

## How we respond to compelled disclosure

ZK may disclose personally-identifying information or other information we collect about you to law enforcement in response to a valid subpoena, court order, warrant, or similar government order, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our property or rights, or those of third parties or the public at large. In complying with court orders and similar legal processes, ZK strives for transparency. When permitted, we will make a reasonable effort to notify users of any disclosure of their information, unless we are prohibited by law or court order from doing so, or in rare, exigent circumstances.

## How you can access and control the information we collect

If you're already a ZK user, you may access, update, or alter your basic user profile information by going to [forum.zkoss.org](http://forum.zkoss.org/questions/) and clicking on your user name. Or contact us at [info@zkoss.org](mailto:info@zkoss.org). 

### Data Retention and Deletion

ZK will retain User Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.

We may retain certain User Personal Information indefinitely, unless you delete it or request its deletion. For example, we don’t automatically delete inactive user accounts, so unless you choose to delete your account, we will retain your account information indefinitely.

If you would like to cancel your account or delete your User Personal Information, please contact us at [info@zkoss.org](mailto:info@zkoss.org). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements, but barring legal requirements, we will delete your full profile (within reason) within 30 days. 

## How we communicate with you

We will use your email address to communicate with you, if you’ve subscribed to receive related notifications about ZK, and when necessary. You have a lot of control over how your email address is used and shared on and through ZK. You may manage your communication preferences in your profile in ZK forum.

Depending on your email settings, ZK may occasionally send notification emails about new features, requests for feedback, important policy changes, or offer customer support. We also send marketing emails, but only with your consent. You can unsubscribe any time.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ZK may change our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will provide notification to Users of material changes to this Privacy Policy through our Website or sending email to the email address specified in your account. For changes to this Privacy Policy that do not affect your rights, we encourage visitors to check this page frequently.

## Contacting ZK

Questions regarding ZK's Privacy Policy or information practices should be sent to [info@zkoss.org](mailto:info@zkoss.org).
